Sooyong Lee

Educational Psychology, The University of Texas at Austin

□ +1 737 865 0618 | Sooyongl09@utexas.com | □ 0000-0002-7964-4508 | □ sooyongl/

Professional Summary _____

As a psychometrician, I specialize in applying contemporary statistical theories and techniques to my work. My research interests center around developing and utilizing statistical models, including structural equation modeling (SEM), multilevel modeling (MLM), item response theory (IRT), and mixture modeling. In my recent work, I have placed particular emphasis on Bayesian estimation as a means of modeling the relationships between variables.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, Texas

Ph.D., Major in Quantitative Methods in Educational Psychology

2017-Present

Korea University M.A., MAJOR IN EDUCATIONAL STATISTICS AND MEASUREMENT Seoul, Republic of Korea

2014-2017

Research experience

CGS PhD Career Pathways project

Graduate Research Assistant

2018/9-2019/5

Data analysis for surveys to collect data on the career pathways of past and present STEM and humanities PhD stu-

President's Award for Global Learning (PAGL)

Graduate Research Assistant

PRESIDENT'S AWARD FOR GLOBAL LEARNING (PAGL)

2019/1-2019/8

 Designing a culturally appropriate mobile application to increase mental health literacy and self-care habits among South Korean young adults

COE Full-Time Tenured and Tenure-Track Faculty

Graduate Research Assistant

2019/9-2019/12

• Data analysis for surveys of graduate programs of education at the University of Texas at Austin

maat package development project

Graduate Research Assistant

NORTHWEST EVALUATION ASSOCIATION (NWEA)

2019/9-2020/5

Development of MAAT package for Computerized Adaptive Testing for Northwest Evaluation Association (NWEA)

FLPS project Graduate Research Assistant

• Development of FLPS package for Fully-latent Principal Stratification

Embedded Standard Setting (ESS)

Intern

CREATIVE MEASUREMENT SOLUTIONS LLC

2020/6-2020/8

2021/9-Present

Internship for developing Shiny app for Embedded Standard Setting

Embedded Standard Setting (ESS)

Intern

CREATIVE MEASUREMENT SOLUTIONS LLC

2021/6-2021/8

Internship for developing ESS package for Embedde Standard Setting

Publications

IES GRANT

Cory L. Cobb, Charles R. Martínez, Jr., **Sooyong Lee**, Tae Kyoung Lee, & Elma I. Lorenzo-Blanco (2021). Acculturation trajectories differ by youth age at arrival and time in residency among Latino immigrant families in a US emerging immigrant context. *International Journal of Intercultural Relations*. 81, 79-93. DOI:10.1016/j.ijintrel. 2021.01.005.

2022

- Seung Choi, Sangdon Lim, Luping Niu, **Sooyong Lee**, Christina M. Schneider, Jay Lee, & Garron J. (2022). maat: An R Package for Multiple Administrations Adaptive Testing. *Applied Psychological Measurement*. 46-1, 73-74. DOI:10.1177/01466216211049212.
- **Sooyong Lee**, Suhwa Han, & Seung W. Choi (2022). DIF Detection With Zero-Inflation Under the Factor Mixture Modeling Framework. *Educational and Psychological Measurement*. 82-4, 678-704. DOI: 10.1177/00131644211028995.
- **Sooyong Lee** & Tiffany A. Whittaker (2022). Comparison of Three Approaches to Class Enumeration in Growth Mixture Modeling when Time Structures are Variant Across Latent Classes. *Structural Equation Modeling: A Multi-disciplinary Journal*. 29, 23-35. DOI:10.1080/10705511.2021.1956320.
- **Sooyong Lee** & Tiffany A. Whittaker (2022). Parallel Process Latent Growth Modeling with Multivariate Confounders/Suppresson Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal. DOI: 10.1080/10705511.2022.2133774.
- **Sooyong Lee**, Kahyun Lee, & Tiffany A. Whittaker (2022). Application of Associative Discrete-Time Survival Analysis Using Latent Transition Specification. *Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal*. DOI: 10.1080/10705511.2022.2138892.

Program

Program	
<pre>Embeded Standard Setting • https://sooyonglee.shinyapps.io/ESS_test/</pre>	Shiny application 2021
<pre>GRshiny: Graded response model • https://sooyonglee.shinyapps.io/GRShiny/</pre>	Shiny application 2022
<pre>Embeded Standard Setting • https://sooyongl.github.io/EmStanS/</pre>	R package 2022
<pre>maat package • https://choi-phd.github.io/maat/</pre>	R package 2022
<pre>flps package • https://sooyongl.github.io/flps/</pre>	R package 2022
<pre>GRshiny package • https://sooyongl.github.io/GRShiny/</pre>	R package 2023
<pre>clavaan package • https://github.com/sooyongl/clavaan</pre>	R package 2023